<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Fall of paganism on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Fall of paganism on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pagan complacency</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/pagan_complacency_watts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/pagan_complacency_watts/</guid>
      <description>Author Edward Watts is a professor and Alkiviadis Vassiliadis Endowed Chair in Byzantine Greek History at the University of California, San Diego. He is the author of The Final Pagan Generation: Rome’s Unexpected Path to Christianity (2015), Mortal Republic: How Rome Fell into Tyranny (2018) and The Eternal Decline and Fall of Rome: The History of a Dangerous Idea (2021), among others. He lives in Carlsbad, California.
Libanius&amp;rsquo;s appeal Late in 386 CE, Libanius, a 72-year-old teacher of rhetoric from the Syrian metropolis of Antioch, penned an oration addressed to the Roman emperor Theodosius I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०२ Muted intolerance</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/02_Muted_intolerance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/02_Muted_intolerance/</guid>
      <description>Inculcation of &amp;ldquo;asebeia&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;not believing in the gods of the state&amp;rdquo;) as an offense was introduced in ancient Greece and used as an easy way to prosecute philosophers. Socrates was killed on such a charge (though devout, there were political problems with him as a gadfly irritating the Athenian horse, though ).  &amp;ldquo;The specifics of the charge were that his reference to his personal daimōn constituted an attempt to introduce a new illicit cult, which would have been centered upon himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०३ Intellectual war</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/03_Intellectual_war/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/03_Intellectual_war/</guid>
      <description>Robust intellectual response to Christianity  The neo-platonist tradition and lineage is described in the platonist page.  Christian appropriation  Appropriation of classical (hellenic) thought  socrates, plato etc.. were excellent polytheists. &amp;ldquo;a man (Socrates) who by his own testimony was on a mission from Apollon.&amp;rdquo;   &amp;ldquo;Through Augustine (354–430) in the West and the 4th-century Cappadocian Fathers (Basil, Gregory of Nyssa, Gregory of Nazianzus) in the East as well as the pseudo-epigraphic writings of Dionysius the Areopagite (early 6th century), Neoplatonism profoundly influenced the emergence of mainstream and not so mainstream Christian theology (John Scotus Eriugena, Thomas Aquinas, Duns Scotus, Meister Eckhart).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>०४ Christianization</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/04_Christianization_of_Roman_empire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/fall_of_paganism/04_Christianization_of_Roman_empire/</guid>
      <description>Summary  Christians were far more willing to take consistent and forceful political action in favor of their religion (rather than &amp;ldquo;Rome&amp;rdquo;). The diverse pagan traditions in the Empire didn&amp;rsquo;t begin to think of themselves as one religion until the Christians in power began taking uniform action against them.  Constantine and Constantius 324-361  We see a pattern of slow start, followed by a sudden quickening. Privileging christians: &amp;ldquo;Constantine himself apparently endorsed this goal and tried to further it through a series of legislative and administrative measures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>