<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Free man on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Free man on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>gangAdhara&#39;s route</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/gangAdhara-route/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/gangAdhara-route/</guid>
      <description>Background  My and Ramya&amp;rsquo;s parents come from a background where monthly salary was the only source of income and was sufficient to take care of food, shelter and education. Travel was limited to summer vacation to grandparents home. But that life was very enjoyable. Lots of family time was the foundation stone.  Transition  When we both started earning. We were clearly products of an education that focussed of employability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money vs Freedom: GangFit</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/gang_fit_quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/gang_fit_quote/</guid>
      <description>From GangFit 3 by Mark Baker/ GuruAnaerobic:
 There are 2 types of individual who trade freedom for money.
1 The employed (millions of these). They spend all their weekdays working for money. They earn money so they can pay bills and feel free at the weekend
2 The individual who is never satisfied - they want more money. The business owner/megarich, entrepreneur, wanker, etc. They are boring show-offs and even more boring company; they only talk about making money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quit selling time for money</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/quit_selling_time_for_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/economics/freedom/quit_selling_time_for_money/</guid>
      <description>The calculation You can quit selling your time and toil for money and dedicate yourself to doing exactly what you want:
 If you are able to figure out a situation where you (and your dependents) can today live with an adequate quality of life for 500$ per month (= 33000₹ in 2016) [this is just an example – plug in any number you like], if you (and dependents) expect to live x years, if you have accumulated 500*12x = 6000x dollars (eg.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>