<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Emperor Julian</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-27_emperor-julian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-27_emperor-julian/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago when we were yapping away on the then latest production of the socialist academic Jared Diamond, Guns Germs Steel Blah blah, we turned our attention to two historical incidents which were reasonably faithfully described by him. One was the destruction of the Native South Americans by the Spanish conquistadors and the other was the cannibalizing of one Austronesian tribe the Moriori by another the Maori. Given his Marxist bent it is not at all surprising that he went on to equate the two events, and try to explain them through his universalist view of geographic contingency, which he repeats ad nauseum in that long-winding tome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hekate</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-16_hekate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-16_hekate/</guid>
      <description>Another point I shall consider is the role of the great goddess Hekate in Neoplatonic thought. Hekate in Neoplatonism plays a strikingly parallel role to mAyA in uttaramImAMsa and prakR^iti in sAMkhya. She is described in the Chaldaean oracles to have emerged from the “primary entity/being” (the Neoplatonic equivalent of puruSha or brahman) and separates the two “fires”- the “purely intellectual fire” that belongs to the primary entity/being and the material fire from which the cosmos arises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some considerations on Neoplatonism</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-16_some-considerations-on-neoplatonism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-16_some-considerations-on-neoplatonism/</guid>
      <description>I have always believed, since I was probably 11 years old, that it was important to study Neoplatonic thought and ritual. This is particularly important because it was one of the sister systems of our own, and was the only world philosophy with a reasonably comparable depth and scope. Importantly, as we are the only surviving heathens in the world with an unbroken link to our ancient traditions firstly of the shruti and then of the Agama-s, we alone, are in the unique position to study Neoplatonism from an insider’s perspective, which is entirely lacking for the western students of Graeco-Roman thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The makings of &#34;Islamic Science&#34;</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-28_the-makings-of-islamic-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/mediterranian/MT_lekhAH/2006-08-28_the-makings-of-islamic-science/</guid>
      <description>“In the time of the Hellenes and during the early days of the empire of the Rum the sciences were honoured and enjoyed universal respect. From an already solid and grandiose foundation, they were raised to greater heights every day, until the Christian religion made its appearance among the Rum; this was a fatal blow to the edifice of learning; its traces disappeared and its pathways were effaced”
-Abu al-Hasan Ali ibn al-Husayn al-Masudi, the scientist from Baghdad, who lived in the 900s of the CE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>