<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Motion on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Motion on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimney</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/chimney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/chimney/</guid>
      <description>Parameters  Suction power. Should suffice to change air 10 times per hour.  Alternate guide: If kitchen is in separate room, 600 m3/h suffices. Else, good to go for 1200 m3/h.   Size: 60x60 (2-4 burners), 90cm (3-5 burners) Autoclean: Better suction power and life.  Turbine blower forces air to move to chimney walls (oil goes thence to a collection bowl, which should be washed every month). Thermal auto-clean - evaporate oil etc from insides of motor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloth washing</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/coth_washing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/coth_washing/</guid>
      <description>Washing machines are more water efficient than hand washing - but consume more electricity (obviously).
Front loaders seem to use less water, result in less water retention in clothes, are more energy efficient - RW. But as of 2020, top loaders seem to be catching up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dish washing</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/dish_washing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/dish_washing/</guid>
      <description>Situation  Standard dimensions noted elsewhere. &amp;ldquo;drain pipe run on the floor level or at a certain height. - The drain water comes out from machine through a pump. As per the specification of the machine this can pump drain water up to approximately 1m height.&amp;rdquo; Not suitable for use with hard-water (borewell).+++(5)+++  Cost  Running cost 2020 INR - Electricity ~ 150 Consumables ~ 200 . Time: 10 minutes per loading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevator</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/elevator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/elevator/</guid>
      <description>Types  Gearless (no oil, less energy) geared Hydraulic. (No pit needed. BUt more maintenance.)  Features  Coated steel belts - zero lubrication. Need for machine room. Finishing - Stainless steel vs fabric. Door opening: Automatic vs manual. Side telescopic vs center. Safety: typically allow getting descending to the next lower floor in case of power loss.  Space  Typical Pit depth 1350mm = 53.14 in  Cost Installation  Depends on capacity, number of stops, technology, lift permit, scaffolding, electrical work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fan</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/fan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/power/motion/fan/</guid>
      <description>They don’t cool rooms, they just provide air circulation in the room to cool you.  Metrics  Air Delivery : example 225 CMM (Cubic Meters per Minute) Number of blades  More blades - less speed, but also less noisy.   Blade sweep. In ceiling fans: 600mm (2ft), 1200 mm (4 ft), 1400mm (5 ft) are common. Greater sweep is like adding more blades plus greater reach for air.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>