<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;brAhmam on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/brAhma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;brAhmam on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/brAhma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Classical period</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/brAhma/Classical_period/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/brAhma/Classical_period/</guid>
      <description>mahAvIra the digambara munI, who gave up everything to conquer himself.
buddha buddha gautama shramaNa, philosophical and social revolutionary, who (unfortunately) opened up paths towards Ananda to a broader section of the society. This led to an unfortunate increase in ascetic tendencies in hindu society.
pANini pANini, the bhArgava (baudhAyanIya-pravarAdhyAye bhRguNAM sUchyAm 30), saMskRta grammarian extraordinaire, great genius.
akShapAda the gautama author of nyAya-sUtra-s.
kaNAda the kashyapa author of the vaisheShika-sUtra-s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian republic</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/brAhma/Indian_republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/brAhma/Indian_republic/</guid>
      <description>bhaktivEkdAnta-svAmI prabhupada, who brought gauDIya bhakti-vEdAnta to the hippies.
BKS IyengAr IyengAr, who took yOga-Asanas abroad, free thinking shishya of kRShNamAchArya, who shook off disease to gain health.
MS subbulakShmI MS subbulakShmI, daughter of a dEvadAsI, who remained a dEvadAsI in the truest sense, bhakti-vairAgya-saMpannA, divine voice who moved even the lay person and the foreigner to tears, bhArata-ratna. A great donor and patriot - who donated Masaysay award money to Phillipines, her new golden bangles towards the 1965 Indo-Pak war funds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule of the European invaders</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/brAhma/Rule_of_the_European_invaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/brAhma/Rule_of_the_European_invaders/</guid>
      <description>Balashastri Jambhekar (1812-1846), had mastered several subjects like physics, chemistry, astronomy, botany, geology, geography, history, mathematics, psychology; grasped nearly one dozen languages like Sanskrit, Hindi, Bengali, Kannada, Gujarati, Telagu, English, Greek, Latin, French and Persian; in his early 20s; published several school books on calculus, geometry &amp;amp; geography, started paper Digdarshan which carried articles on physics, chemistry, psychology, palaeogeography, wrote a 6 volume series &amp;ldquo;Jyotissastra&amp;rdquo;, dissuaded &amp;ldquo;superstition&amp;rdquo;. [TW]
arumuka nalavAr arumuka nalavAr, the dvaita saiddhAntika shaiva, a brAhmaNa in deed despite not being born in the brAhmaNa-jAti, reprimanded the brAhmaNas of TN for the rate at which they were giving up the veda, who produced vigorous critiques of the Christianity and impeded missionary activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The era of jihAds</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/brAhma/The_era_of_jihAds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/brAhma/The_era_of_jihAds/</guid>
      <description>The anonymous brAhmaNas who informed Ahmad ibn Yahya ibn Ishak al-Rawandi.  abhinava-gupta abhinava-gupta, genius tAntrika yOgI rasika, author of tantrAlOka and abhinava-bhAratI.
kalhaNa kalhaNa, the kAshmIra-paNDita, to whom we owe the historical sentimental recollection rAja-tarangiNI.
yAmunAchArya yAmunAchArya ALvandAr, clever debator and great perceptor (who incidentally authored a lost work on the kAshmIra-(pAncharAtrika)-Agama-prAmANya).
bhAskarAchArya 2 the great polymath mathematician.
 As his disciple wrote: अष्टौ व्याकरणानि षट् च भिषजां व्याचष्ट ताः संहिताः</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>