<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Indo-aryan on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Indo-aryan on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Aryan invasion</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/Arya-invasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/Arya-invasion/</guid>
      <description>yAmnAya corded-ware baltic-fatyanovo abashevo sintashta andronovo nordquvist 2020     narasimhan19-admixture     yAmnAya corded-ware farmer mixture 18   The mAnasatarangiNIkAra and others have spoken on this here: MT1803, N201803, 20151212 (mindmup map, img, base file here), RK16, H17,20151219, 2015BX, 201209. Also see notes in the &amp;ldquo;current genetics section&amp;rdquo; below.
The (more credible) AIT narrative of Bronze age events.
Old home Indo-Aryans initially resided in the area around/ beyond the Black Sea, and were familiar with cold and long dawns (as evidenced by some parts of the Vedic texts - long ashvina-shastra to be recited at dawn).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Arya consolidation</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/Arya-consolidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/Arya-consolidation/</guid>
      <description>Spread within India  From baudhAyana and manu, it is clear that kuru-pAnchAla realm was where major brAhmaNa vedic consolidation happened. Gradually, this culture and its carriers (mainly in the form of brAhmaNa-s) spread elsewhere in India and beyond. {GA_17}  baudhAyana-dharma-sUtra implies that vaidika karma-s can only be conducted in the &amp;ldquo;madhya-desha&amp;rdquo;, not even in kalinga, vanga, AraTTa, gAndhAra etc.. - going where expiation is required [TW]. Yet, we observe baudhAyana-s and vaidika-s in kerala and TN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final composition</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/varNa-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/varNa-composition/</guid>
      <description>kShatriya-s  &amp;ldquo;The brAhmaNas (brahmins) and the kShatriyas are in essense the descendents of the aristocracy or elite families of the invading Aryans. Overtime the kShatriya fold adopted other Indo-Aryan tribes outside of the pa~nchajana-ikShvAku orthodoxy, and various “honorary” kShatriyas of diverse ethnic backgrounds. These newcomers displaced or supplemented the original kShatriyas to a significant degree.&amp;rdquo; [MT1]  brAhmaNa-s  &amp;ldquo;However, in the case of the brahmin the displacement was less significant, though there was a noticeable ethnic diversification through the process of anuloma marriage and the 7 generation rule of ascent to brahmin-hood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rAjput muslim alliance</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/rAjput-muslim-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/rAjput-muslim-alliance/</guid>
      <description>Hindu service during late Mogol days  &amp;ldquo;The rAjpUt-s, though diminished in their national sense since the days of the great struggle of mahArANa pratAp and his son amar singh, were still not devoid of their Hindu affinities&amp;hellip; Their position was not unlike that of most common Hindus of today – they may work faithfully for the enemy, despite having their sub-current Hindu sympathies still intact. &amp;quot; MT &amp;ldquo;There were still pockets of brave rAjpUt resistance that was no less in fury than that of the mahArATTa-s&amp;hellip; There were also great uprisings of the bundela-s Chatrasal, prahAr singh and devI singh and another rAjpUt bhagavant singh against the Moslems in this period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sindh betrayal</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/sindh_betrayal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/sindh_betrayal/</guid>
      <description>Reference: McLean thesis here.  Difference in early collaboration  &amp;ldquo;There are clear discrepancies between the Buddhists and the Hindus of Sind both in their immediate response to the Arab invasion .and in the long term effect which the occupation had on them. That is, Buddhists tended to collaborate to a significantly greater extent and at an earlier date than did Hindus and, more&amp;rsquo; importantly, Buddhism disappeared completely as a viable religious system during the Arab period while Hinduism has continued to survive, in varying conditions of prosperity, until the present day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steppe remnants</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/steppe_remnants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/steppe_remnants/</guid>
      <description>Kurus  There were people with uniquely Indian admixture operating even in Central Asia around the time of the Aryan transition. This suggests that Indo-Aryan power was actually straddling their steppe base &amp;amp; northern India. I believe the memory of the former is that of the uttara-kuru-s. &amp;hellip; [I] hold that a branch of these steppe kuru-s re-emerged with another allied clan the kamboja much later on the Iranians side to form the elite of the hAkamAnashIya dynasty.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>