<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Polity क्षात्रम् on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Polity क्षात्रम् on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-preta</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/anti-preta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/anti-preta/</guid>
      <description>Alas many mahArAja-s were given to excesses and decadence - they competed with each other in their neglect of rAjadharma. None the less, there were many exceptions, and commoners stepped up.
rANI abbakka of the chauTa dynasty the simple queen of tuLunADu, who fought the portuguese. [SW]
pRthvI-nArAyaNa-shAha-deva of nepAla the gUrkhAli rAjA, a mantra-sAdhaka, who beat back the British invasion, who drove out jesuit missionaries.
puli tevan who in 1751 demanded British to quit India, fought off various muhammedan proxies and allies, was finally murdered by Yusuf Khan aka Marutanayaga [TW].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mAdanna akkanna</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/mAdanna_akkanna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/mAdanna_akkanna/</guid>
      <description>Intro  madaNNa and akkaNNa, who protected the dharma as powerful ministers under qutub shAhis, collaborators with shivAji. &amp;ldquo;The family of mAdaNNA came from the town of Hanamkonda, Northeast of Bhaganagari, where under rudradeva kAkatIya a large temple of viShNu and sUrya had been constructed. The father of the brothers, bhANu-jI paNDita was a revenue administrator of the town and was named after one of the deities of the town. The son mAdhava paNDita (mAdaNNA) and arkarAja paNDita (akkaNNa) were also named after the two deities of the temple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maratha age</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/</guid>
      <description>kAnhojI jEDhE deshmukh deputed by Shahaji himself to protect shivAjI, who as a senior nobleman at a crucial juncture (during the Afzal Khan campaign) inspired and convinced all the deshkumkh-s to fight for svarAj rather than buckle towards Adil Shah, played major role in planning and executing battle of pratApgaD against Afzal Khan. - &amp;ldquo;Kanhoji Jedhe went to Rajgad with the firmans received from Afzal Khan and publicly declared that he would relinquish his lands and his earnings to Shivaji but not join Afzal Khan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>shivAjI शिवराजः</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/shiva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/shiva/</guid>
      <description>shiva/ shivAji kShatrapati (6 April 1627 or 19 Feb. 1630 – 3 April 1680)
Impact  यथान्यैरुक्तम् -  नैकदुर्गविजेतारं धर्मकण्टकनाशनम्। शिवराजं वन्देऽहं खानोदरविदारकम्॥ प्रातिपश्चन्द्रलेखैव वर्धिष्णुर् विश्ववन्दिता। शाहसूनोश् शिवस्यैषा मुद्रा भद्राय राजते॥ कासिहू ते कला जाती मथुरा मसीद होती सिवाजी न होतो तौ सुनति होत सबकी - भूषणः।    Brilliant concept  under divine guidance, conceptualized and realized hindu svarAjya (evident even at a young age - see letter written to Dadaji Naras Prabhu at age 15 or 18 SG-academia), sought to rid hindusthAna of the mohammedan menace (letter to Jayasimha archive, P1 points 51 to 70,  In south: &amp;ldquo;using the Qutbshah’s resources shivAjI conquered the fort of Gingee and extended his domain into the south ending the careers of several Jihadis and putting a check on the mlechCha-s who were surrounding the coast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vIra sAvarkar</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/sAvarkara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/sAvarkara/</guid>
      <description>Intro vIra vinAyaka dAmodara sAvarkara; chitpAvana, hindu nationalist, the visionary who caused massive Hindu recruitment into the British Indian army - a factor which would prove critical during partition, social reformer.
Pro independence contributions  The first political leader to daringly set Absolute Political Independence as India&amp;rsquo;s goal (1900). Daringly performed a bonfire of foreign (English) clothes (1905). Organized revolutionary movement for Bharat&amp;rsquo;s Independence on international level (1906). The first law student who was not called to the English Bar despite having passed his examination and observed the necessary formalities, as he asked freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>