<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Steppe radiations on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/steppe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Steppe radiations on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/steppe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Huns</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/steppe/huN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/steppe/huN/</guid>
      <description>The Hun Khanates starting from Shanyu Motun Tegin (probably originally pronounced as Shanyu Bagā’tur) learned the steppe Indo-Iranian style mobile warfare and made it a mechanism that allowed the Altaic people to overthrow the steppe Iranians and seize their steppe lands for themselves. They were able deploy this mode of warfare effectively on the Han Chinese empire and established a system where mobile steppe warriors could defeat much larger armies raised by sedentary populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tanguts</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/steppe/tangut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/steppe/tangut/</guid>
      <description>Early history  They were of Tibetan ethnicity, with significant Altaic input.  &amp;ldquo;From the Chinese evidence we observe that their predecessors or at least that of the ruling Ngvemi clan of the Tanguts might have originally had links to the Tabgach (Chinese: Tuoba) people with Altaic affinities: they were either early Turks or Mongols or a distinct extinct branch of the Altaic family. &amp;quot; &amp;ldquo;In their earliest days going back to the 300-400 CE they appear to have had marriage relationships with the para-Mongolic Tuyuhun (Tuguhun) Khaganate and played a role in the formation of this state in between the Tibetans and the Chinese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tungustic</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/steppe/tungustic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/steppe/tungustic/</guid>
      <description>1280px-Linguistic map of the Tungusic languages   Jurchen (proto-Manchu), Jin &amp;ldquo;The Han of the Song with aid from coethnic Hans within the Khitan empire made an alliance with the Khitan vassals, the Jurchen from Manchuria belonging to the Tungoosid branch of the Altaic peoples. The latter in 1124 CE defeated the Khitan and usurped all of their possessions in China, Manchuria and northern Korea.&amp;rdquo; {MT}
&amp;ldquo;The Jurchen were initially allied to the Khitan and formed part of their their invasionary force during the conquest of the Koreans.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>