<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Resources on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Resources on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Charity</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/resources/charity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/resources/charity/</guid>
      <description>Traditional view  Various iShTa-s and pUrti-s were said to earn merit, even as part of daily rituals like vaishvadeva  These include supporting scholars, providing food to various people (even to chaNDAla-s in the daily vaishvadeva) [MT]    Current situation  2014 numbers - [news]  &amp;ldquo;India has climbed 24 places (from 93) in its overall ranking of 69 out of the 135 countries that participated in the World Giving Index 2014 survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/resources/economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/resources/economics/</guid>
      <description>[Incomplete]
Gems were sold on the streets of vijayanagara.
Disparity in wealth. zamIndAri system by the British and Mogols impoverished people.
&amp;ldquo;The British exploited India? So did the Muslim regimes. Land tax was very high under the Delhi Sultanate and peasant famines as frequent as under the British.&amp;rdquo;
National wealth decline During 1-1000 AD, India topped the world with more than 50% of the world&amp;rsquo;s GDP and China stood second. Between 1500-1700, China overtook pushing India to second position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/resources/food/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/resources/food/</guid>
      <description>British Famines  Factors there include artificial famines (Eg: 1943 Bengal famine), food exports at time of famine (Ja). Lytton&amp;rsquo;s famine exacerbation. (TE) Churchill diverted essential grain away from Bengal to *reserves* in Europe. The time of severe famines in colonial Asia coincided with lack of famines in the colonist homelands.  Salt  The British, with their high salt tax (and a big hedge, which in 1869, extended from the Indus to the Mahanadi in Madras, a distance of 2,300 miles; guarded by nearly 12,000 men and petty officers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>