<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>End of the Maharattas – I</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2004-05-13_end-of-the-maharattas-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2004-05-13_end-of-the-maharattas-i/</guid>
      <description>An important lesson is there to be learnt from what happened between 1795 to 1818 vis-a-vis the Maharattas. Bajirao II handed himself up to British protection as he was in conflict with Daulatrao Shinde. Shinde was in turn in locked in enemity with Yashvant and Vithoji Holkar and the other major Maharatta chiefs like Gaikwad in Gujarat and Bhosle of Nagpur. Vithoji Holkar was given to banditry and he began large scale thievery and raiding along with his Pendharis north of the Krishna river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Bajirao-I</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2006-02-28_on-bajirao-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2006-02-28_on-bajirao-i/</guid>
      <description>The muni and me stood on the elevated wall of the plinth of the shanivAr palace (Shaniwar palace) on a blazing Indian afternoon about an year ago. That was all that was left of the palace built by the famed Peshwa, who had raised the Maharattas to their greatest glory. The Peshva was a Brahmin of the coastal community different from the interior brahmins of Maharashtra. Some have believed that these Brahmins had origins elsewhere in North India, but genetically they are not very different from other “pa~ncha-draviDa” brahmin groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sant Ramadas’ letter to Sambhaji</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2004-05-23_sant-ramadas-letter-to-sambhaji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2004-05-23_sant-ramadas-letter-to-sambhaji/</guid>
      <description>When Sambhaji seized power he invited his father’s advisor the bhakti saint Ramadas to meet him. However, Ramadas displeased by Sambhaji’s brutalities that accompanied his accession refused to meet him. His disciples however begged on him to advice the prince. Accordingly he sent him the following letter:
“Always be on guard and never lower you guard. Control your temper and be good and kind towards others. Forgive your subjects for their faults and bind them to your person by making them happy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The death of Hambirrao</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2004-06-02_the-death-of-hambirrao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2004-06-02_the-death-of-hambirrao/</guid>
      <description>By 1687 the Mogol tyrant from Dilli, had fulfilled the dream cherished by his ancestors since the days of the tyrant Akbar, namely to conquest of the Deccan Sultanates. In a whirl wind campaign Awrangzeeb had conquered the Adil Shahi kingdom, founded by the prince Adil Khan the brother of the Ottoman sultan Mehmet II Fathi of Turkey and the Qutb Shahi kingdom which was bravely defended to the very end by the Turk, Abdur Razzak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of Sambhaji</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2004-06-13_the-end-of-sambhaji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2004-06-13_the-end-of-sambhaji/</guid>
      <description>After the death of Hambirrao Mohite, the Mogol armies pressed hard on the Maharattas forcing them to the strongest fortresses in Sahayadris for shelter. Awrangzeeb’s army was struck by bubonic plague, but he continued moving his vast divisions westwards to encircle the Maharattas. He also sent a division towards Bangalore and Tamil Nad to cut out the southern base of the Marathas. Sambhaji, without his ace general was entirely in the control of his base Kanyakubja Brahmin minister Kalash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War in the Konkan</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2004-04-06_war-in-the-konkan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/maratha/MT_lekhAH/2004-04-06_war-in-the-konkan/</guid>
      <description>Very little has been recorded of the valiant freedom struggle in the Konkan in the horror years of Indian history. The Konkans on the west coast of India had long been the bastion of the Indic civilization that withstood external attacks due to the protective influence of the Western Ghats. The first major wave of Islamic onslaughts on the region was initiated by Alla-ad-din Khalji when he dispatched his ace commander Maliq Kaffr to wage Jihad on the ancient dynasty of the Kadambas, who were the principal rulers of the Konkans.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>