<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gAzi vs hindu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/gAzi_downing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gAzi vs hindu on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/gAzi_downing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>East</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/gAzi_downing/east/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/gAzi_downing/east/</guid>
      <description>ananga-bhImadeva III Chodaganga of kalinga who offered the kaling throne to jagannAtha, united his people, resisted the mlecCha-s in 1215 CE, rebuilt the old Keshari fortress as a Fortress-City, Abhinab Bidanasi Kataka- ‘The New Fortress of Varanasi’, and dedicated to the Chandi of the temple [RL].
gajapati narasimhadeva I of kalinga who reconquered vanga, constructed konArka-temple.
General kapilendradeva Routray of kalinga who crushed the Sultan of Jaunpur, defeated the armies of Bengal, recovered orissa, with his able minister Gopinath Mahapatra deposed the old Chodaganga Gajapati Bhanudeva IV, dedicated the throne to jagannAtha, attacked even bahamanI capital bIdar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/gAzi_downing/north/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/gAzi_downing/north/</guid>
      <description>chach of Aror a brAhmaNa who took over the sindhi empire and consolidated it by marriages, arms and appointments - faced the initial arab attack.
dAhira-sena son of chach, who valiantly fought Arab invaders (supported by local betrayers, including bauddha chieftains) to his death with his queen lADI bAi, an upAsaka of hingalAj devI.
Hamirji Gohil 16 year old newly married chieftain of Lathi, who sacrificed his life in 1299 defending the Somnath temple from the attack of Alauddin Khalji .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/gAzi_downing/south/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/persons/xatra/gAzi_downing/south/</guid>
      <description>[![](../../../images/structures/kAkatIya-ruins.jpg]pulakeshin 2 chAlukya emperor, who claimed the throne from his userper regent uncle after fleeing to kolar and allying with bANa and other tribes, defeated all feudatories and neibhors, including a dejected harSha at narmadA, trounced the naval jihaad sent by 636 CE kaliif umar, compannion of muhammad at thAne, who in his last days saw a pallava counter invasion and death at the hands of narasimhavarman.
vikrama chAlukya perhaps one of the greatest of clan after pulakeshin-II.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>