<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;China on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;China on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Christianity</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/preta-repudiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/preta-repudiation/</guid>
      <description>White lotus / red turban rebellion  The White Lotus originated as a hybrid movement of Buddhism and Manichaeism that emphasised strict vegetarianism and permitted men and women to interact freely, which was socially shocking. Like other secret societies, they covered up their unusual or illicit activities as &amp;ldquo;incense-burning ceremonies&amp;rdquo;. Successfully overthrew the yuan, abandoning heterodox roots in the end.  Taiping civil war.  &amp;ldquo;a curious Chinese civil war, which took place in 1850-1860s, whose geopolitical significance is often lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroes</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/heroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/heroes/</guid>
      <description>Taizong, relentlessly legalist expansionist emperor of china, born of a Han father in the lineage of Laozi the founder of Taoism and a mother from a subsidiary clan of Blue Turks, through a series of victories raised the chIna-s to their greatest glory, a tall and powerful man, said to tower imperiously above his cowering fellow chIna-s, a rather impressive personality with a good knowledge of chIna scientific texts and artistic skill in calligraphy, instituted a system with the Taoism and bauddha dharma as the outer coat for the inner core of legalism centered on his persona, adopted Turkic customs such as as allowing chIna women to ride horses and letting his sons live in yurts on the palace-grounds and speaking with them in Turkic, despite his ministers’ advice to the contrary, he clearly outlined his policy of sending the Han to settle all territory he conquered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islam</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/islam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/islam/</guid>
      <description>Yuan period  Persian Sepoy / ispah rebellion in the middle of 14th century in Fujian under the Yuan dynasty. Afterwards many of the foreign Arab and Persian merchants were massacred when the uprising was crushed and their graves desecrated, forcing many of them to flee Quanzhou.  Dungan Rebellion of China [WI]
Prelude  Panthay 17 yr rebellion with heavy Mohammedan element, overlapped with Dungan jihad. &amp;ldquo;Jahangir Khoja→Panthay Rebellion (1 mill dead)→1st Dungan (8-12 mill dead) 1862–77 →2nd Dungan (1895 during 1st S-J war)&amp;rdquo; Religious motivations  sUfi rAshidIn khwAja [TW].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/name/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/name/</guid>
      <description>Hua 華 This character is a self-designation of the Chinese both internally and abroad, e.g. the Chinese minority in Vietnam is known as the Hoa. Its basic meaning is “civilized, elite” (apart from “flower”, with the same character), the opposite meaning of “barbarian”. The Chinese do indeed consider themselves as the civilized ones, as distinct from the barbarians. Hua is unapologetic in its claim to superiority.
Zhong, “middle”, from Zhongguo, “the Middle Kingdom, China”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/sino-tibetan/china/religion/</guid>
      <description>Recent trajectory The communist party tried to eradicate religion starting from the cultural revolution - they tortured monks, destroyed monasteries. But this ceased in 1982. After economic growth in the 1990’s, recognizing a popular feeling of spiritual emptiness, the party promoted religion as an important part of developing a harmonious society, provided they support the party. Those that disagree are suppressed: Eg: Falun Gong, Catholic Church, some Tibetian Buddhism.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>