<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Religion on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Religion on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>0 Old Iranic</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/0_old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/0_old/</guid>
      <description>A sibling of the Arya deva-dharma, a child of the ancestral Indo-Iranian branch of Indo-Aryan. They shared several deva-s with the Arya-s.  deva-s  &amp;ldquo;From the fragments of the pre-Achaemenid Medians and Persians, and also to certain extant the later Parthians and shAkas we observe that the system based on the worship of the Aditya-s (though they are never called that) was the dominant one. Especially, mitra, varuNa, bhaga (who came to be widely transmitted throughout the ancient Iranic sphere - &amp;ldquo;bhAgdAd&amp;rdquo; to the Turks and mongols - &amp;ldquo;bhagaputra/ bhagAtur, ulAn bATar&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 Zoro reconfiguration</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/1_zoro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/1_zoro/</guid>
      <description>yazata-s  &amp;ldquo;In the amesha spenta-s+++(=yazata-s)+++ we find an invention of new devatA-s, in part to conceal the old ones. Thus, the abstractions of vohu-manaH, asha vahishta, and khshathra-vairiya are raised to devatA-s. The abstractions haurvatAt and amaratAt are used to conceal the old demonized twin devatA-s (i.e. the ashvinau).&amp;rdquo; MT-iShmin &amp;ldquo;The old devatA-s mithra (=mitra), baga (=bhaga), airiyaman(=aryaman), vAyu (same), aredvI surA anAhitA (=sarasvatI), haoma (=soma), thworashtar (=tvaShTar), thrita (=trita), apAm-napAt (same), spentA Armaiti (=aramati), yima vivanghat (=yama vaivasvata), and nairyosangha (=narAshaMsa) were, in large part, maintained as is but reconfigured as partisans of the ahuric force directed against the daeva-s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Spread and stasis</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/2_spread_stasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/2_spread_stasis/</guid>
      <description>Continued prosyletizing tendencies Thus, Zoroastrianism expanded by conversion of existing priesthoods in addition to chieftains – just as Islam would later do in Persia. Further, with time, this confederacy expanded and began to convert people of not just other clans but other ‘ethnicities’. It was a strongly proselytizing faith, and also an imperialistic one. Eventually, a particular confederation clicked and they rapidly expanded and created a new empire in the Middle East and C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Christian influx</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/3_preta_suppression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/3_preta_suppression/</guid>
      <description>Initial acceptance &amp;ldquo;Yazdegerd I&amp;rsquo;s reign was a landmark for the Christians in Iran. With the counsel of Roman bishop Marutha, he acknowledged the Church of the East in 410; this led to the establishment of the Iranian church, which would declare its independence from the Roman church in 424. &amp;hellip; One of his gestures of generosity was to permit Christians to bury their dead, which Zoroastrians believed tainted the land. The number of Christian elites in the bureaucracy increased, a flow which continued until the fall of the empire in 651.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Mazdak schism</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/4_mazdak_schism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/4_mazdak_schism/</guid>
      <description>Schism of the liberals Eventually, this ossification gave rise to several waves of new ideologies to counter Zoroastrian “orthodoxy”, movements that became very popular, such as Mazdakism, etc. &amp;ldquo;In 484, Persian king Peroz I was killed on campaign, and most of the Sasanian army was destroyed. This disastrous defeat provoked a crisis of succession and touched off more than a decade of unrest, during which time a renegade Zoroastrian priest named Mazdak (who preached common ownership of possessions—and women) became an influential figure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Resistance</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/6_resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/6_resistance/</guid>
      <description>Intro Nevertheless, the wholesale capitulation of Iran under Arabs was unexpected, even by the radical subversives and defectors. While Iranians were needed to run the affairs of administration, they were unable to engineer a Persianization campaign. Instead, it began to look increasingly like Iran would become Arabized like Syria (a process well laid-out in Islam, to make non-Arabic converts into “mu’arrabeen”).
The evolution of gnostic schools within Islam were continually borrowing from Mithraism, Manichaeism, Zoroastrianism and Buddhism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Hindu refuge</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/7_hindu_refuge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/7_hindu_refuge/</guid>
      <description>Early settlements Some of the mercantile Zoroastrian communities had already set up small communities in India’s Gujarat just before Islam. After the invasion, part of the aristocracy and priesthood fled to join them. Later, more merchants followed, and also people of the professions. These together formed the Parsi community, comprising the 4 castes of Iranian orthodoxy.
During the extermination drive by the Qajars, when life for Zoroastrians was extremely humiliating – being treated as untouchables as per the Islamic concept of “nijasah” – many came to India in the last 2 centuries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 Lessons for Hindus</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/9_lessons_for_hindus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/9_lessons_for_hindus/</guid>
      <description>The dynamics between later Hinduism and Buddhism is worth studying to understand why we have since had this repeated process of counter-religions and counter-priesthoods emerging in India, that often mutate to become not just an antinomian voice within the civilization but downright anti-national. The Indic and transnational Buddhist mercantile networks were at the forefront of arguing for peace and compromise with the new Islamic empire. Little did they know that they would be culled once their role as useful idiots was complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Betrayal to Islam</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/5_betrayal_to_islam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/history/paganology/Aryan/indo-iranian/iranic/persia/religion/5_betrayal_to_islam/</guid>
      <description>Salman aka Mobed Dinyar aka Ruzbeh It is a little known story, that Salman al-Farsi, one of the key companions of Muhammad, was a member of a radical Mazdaki sect. Salman was one of Muhammad’s closest companions, advisors and aides, and was himself an aristocratic Persian convert whose tactical AND gnostic knowledge Muhammad thrived on. Tactically, most famous was his idea at the Battle of Khandaq (the Trench) that saved Islam from being snuffed out in the bud.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>